Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder
of Family First Financial Services, MBA Finance and have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years.
ICICI Prudential Life Insurance has
launched a new Yuli plan after the immense success of the Signature Plan which runs for 100 years, Signature Pension. After
its success, they have also launched another new Yuli plan, Signature Assurance.
This time they have focused on child education, child marriage,
protecting the family and wealth creation because this time they
have not kept the term at 100 years, but only 25 years. They have kept the rider of waiver of premium. Premium
allocation charges are zero. On death, the death benefit will be available immediately. Premium payment
will be waived. The policy will continue till maturity and the family
will also get 10% annual income. This product has been launched with such great features.
Watch this video completely, I am going to explain every feature in detail. If you
like the video, then definitely subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS. Many people
have done it, you should also do it so that you will get more than 300 insurance related videos there
which will help you in your insurance and financial planning. Talking about
ICICI Potential's Signature Ayor Plan, let's start with the main feature
which is the death benefit. I will explain the rest of the common features to you in details later.
Two options are given in death benefit, one is for a sum and the other is for a smart sum. If death
occurs in the sum, then the minimum death benefit or you can pay the premium 10 or 10 times, whichever
you select, that will be the amount you will get. The minimum which is guaranteed or the minimum
death benefit will be 105 on the total premium paid. Talking about smart
benefit, you will get two options in smart benefit which are inbuilt.
You will not have to pay any additional premium for both these options. These
will be found inbuilt in your policy, which includes future secure and family income.
There are also two options in secure, one is maturity protect and one
is with waiver of premium. I will explain maturity protect in details later. First, I
will explain about feature secure. If the customer dies, then
because of this feature of feature secure, all the remaining premiums are waived off. Death benefit
will be available immediately and the policy continues and maturity will also
come. And the second option, which is called family income, you can avail sum assured from zero to 10 per cent.
Age of now, when you go to buy an illustration or policy
, you will find 10 per cent written there. This cannot be said to be less. So, suppose you
pay a premium of Rs. 1 lakh, then there is an insurance cover of 25 lakhs. 25 lakhs at 10 per cent means Rs. 1 lakh
from the time of death till the maturity of the policy, for as many
years as the policy term is pending, this lakh rupees will keep coming to the nominee every year. And the premiums were waived off, which means you
don't have to pay. ICICI is paying the premium for you and
the nominee will get the maturity of the fund value of that premium as well. Loyalty You will also get benefits
which will start from the first two years and you will get it in the gap of every four years.
The average of the fund value of the last eight quarters i.e.
the average of your fund value in the eight quarters in the last two years will be calculated.
The average of that will be given as a loyalty addition to your fund value. It
will be given as loyalty benefit and will be given every four years starting from the first two years. If there
is a person who has purchased this policy and is paying premium in it but
he has never done parcel withdrawal and he survives and his fund value
becomes less than the premium, becomes less than the estimated premium, then the total
premiums paid will be given to him as maturity. This is
called maturity protect. Maturity benefit is a different thing. This is maturity protect
where you get the total premiums paid if your fund value
becomes less than the estimated premium. You can understand maturity product in simple language
as capital guarantee i.e. the premium you pay will be the same. So you
will definitely get it, it will never be less than this.
Your total fund value will never be less than the premium you pay. Maturity benefit: Now, in all other plans,
what is the maturity benefit is that they get maturity only on survival.
In this plan, you will get maturity even if you survive, you
will get it even if you do not survive because ICICI Prudential will pay the rest of the premium and
your nominees will get the maturity benefit. So, in both the cases, you will get maturity benefit.
What fund value will you get on maturity Now let us understand
the benefit illustration of this best investment Uli plan of
ICICI Potential If you see the objective of this plan
, it has been done keeping in mind child education, legacy planning, wealth creation and family protection.
The name of the plan is Signature Air, the age of the customer is 35 years and here
you will get the fund value on maturity. The definition of maturity protect
is given here. Here how much insurance cover
will you have? If you have taken a premium of ₹ lakh, then there will be a cover of 25 lakhs. The benefit of waiver of premium is also
given here. You will get an income of ₹ lakh. On 10, income option
has been taken here. On maturity benefit you will get the fund value. Here you will pay the premium. You are paying Rs. 10 lakhs
for 10 years and your maturity will come in the year 2049.
You have taken a policy term of 25 years. In this policy, you can also top up, can also do parcel withdrawal,
can also switch, can also do SWP. EPW
has sold policies to about 10 crore people so far. This is a big company worth Rs. 3 lakh crores. There
is also quick settlement ratio and in this plan, the customer has also added accidental cover of Rs. 25 lakhs and disability
cover of Rs. 25 lakhs as riders. Here you will see Signature Ayor which
is a non-participating linked plan, that is, it is a share market based plan where
the customer gets an insurance cover of Rs. 25 lakhs by paying a premium of Rs. 1 lakhs
for 10 years and here he is investing in different funds
like he is investing at Rs. 10 in Momentum Fund, Rs. 5 in Value Insul Fund, Rs.
10 in Indian Growth Fund, Rs. 25 in Maximizer Fund. Balance
Advantage The fund is at Rs 10 per cent, the multi-cap fund is at Rs 10 per cent, the mid-cap
fund is at Rs 10 per cent, the opportunity fund is at Rs 5 per cent, the blue chip fund is at Rs 10 per cent. If you want, you
can invest in any one fund, or two funds,
and can also switch. If you have not taken the option of systematic withdrawal here,
you can avail the family income benefit here
for Rs 25,000,000. This is your basic premium of Rs 2 lakh.
The premium of the rider is Rs 3,100 for the accidental one and you
are getting the benefit of disabilities cover for Rs 2,366. So, you will get this policy for Rs 25,6450. Now here
you will see, let us go to part B and see how all the benefits are there,
suppose you are paying a premium of Rs 1 lakh. The biggest
thing is that here your premium allocation charges are zero, which is
approximately the same in other plans of this insurance company. 6, then here you get Rs. 000
every year, if that is saved then the premium allocation charges are zero, secondly here you
will see that you are also getting loyalty addition, you can see here in the column which
will start from the first year, you will
get the fund value average % of the last eight quarters after every 5 years, so you will see this loyalty addition every 5 years, maturity
protect, I have already explained to you that if the fund value decreases,
then you get back all the premiums paid, it is not mentioned here
because here the fund value is already more than the annual premium, if it decreases
then you get back all the premiums paid, here you see the fund value, it
is mandatory to show the table on RRD M8, so according to that
the maturity of 8816 312 will come tax free, now instead of 81 lakhs, by the way,
I am going to tell you in detail further in the fund performance, here the EPU fund
gave 15 20 25 30 If the return is even 12%, then the maturity amount
of 81 lakhs that you are seeing will be around 2 crores 1.97 crores and
if you get a return of 15%, then your tax free maturity will be around 3.80% or 4 crores,
so this is market base, after 5 years
you can withdraw money from this, plus the surrender value will be the fund value only, if
you see here, if you surrender after a year,
if you do not want to withdraw the parcel, then you can withdraw your actual fund value,
now here you will notice one thing, in the last column death benefit
is written as lump sum benefit, whereas what happens in a normal Uli policy, like here
see after 15 years your fund value is 44 lakhs but the death benefit is 225000, so you
must be thinking why it is so less, the fund value and death benefit which is ever higher is that You should get it
because this is a unique plan, if there is a death here, for example,
I will take an example of five years, suppose the customer dies in the fifth year, then
The death benefit there was 25 lakhs, so this ₹ 1 lakh
will be immediately given to the nominee, the rest of the premiums will be waived. The sixth, seventh, eighth, ninth, tenth
premium will be paid by ICICI potential itself and the maturity date of this investment
of ₹ 81 lakh or as per the fund performance will also be given to the nominee and
along with that, when the death occurs in the fifth year, then ₹ 1 lakh or the family income
benefit that you had selected, this ₹ 1 lakh will also
be given to the nominee every year for the next 20 years, that is, in the fifth year. The policy term is 25 years, 20 years are left, so
2.5 lakhs will come in 20 years on maturity. ₹ 81 lakh, if its fund value gives a return of 15
, then a match of ₹ 3.80 crore will also be received. Plus the debt benefit of ₹ 25 lakh has been received immediately and
the policy is running, the premiums have been waived. So in this way you can see the benefit.
Now suppose If the customer died in an accident, then 25 lakh normal cover, 25 lakh
accidental cover, we have also added a rider in it, this one means that the 25 lakh for accident
will be given more, so 50 lakhs will be given to the family immediately, ₹ 1 lakh income is coming every year,
fund value will also be available and you get this rider at very nominal cheap premium,
so you can also add rider, in this way you
can understand this benefit illustration and now after 1st October, you will also get this customer information sheet
in the policy bundle where your policy number will also be mentioned, the category of the product will be mentioned,
what kind of plan have you taken, what riders have you purchased, have you
offered free look, surrender benefit, all this information is available
to you at the beginning of the policy itself on the customer information sheet, where to make a claim,
you can call on customer care, when to complain, if you want to complain, to whom can you do it,
how can you do free look, for how many days, all this information is available here
Under the policy bond, this policy can be purchased by a person between 18 and 50 years of age. Here
you can buy the policy in yearly, monthly and semi-annual mode.
You cannot buy the policy in quarterly mode. You can pay the minimum premium as per the month.
There is no such limit for paying the maximum premium of the policy.
You can select the premium payment term from 5 years to 15 years.
You can buy the policy term between 15 and 25 years as per your need.
In this plan, you will also get the option of systematic withdrawal. Along with partial withdrawal, you
can also avail the benefit of systematic SWP, just like in mutual funds.
Suppose you have decided that you
want 6% of your fund value every year, then 6% of your fund value will automatically come into your account every year.
You can take this AWP in annual mode, quarterly mode and monthly mode as well.
If you want, you can take it after 5 years. The biggest thing is that the biggest
charge that is levied in the Uli policy is the premium allocation charges, which
are not there in this plan, which is a very good thing. Talking about other charges, the FMC
charges, if you take equity based fund, will be 1.35%. If you take money market
fund, then you will be charged 0.75%. Talking about policy admin,
you can take it for maximum per month. Talking about maximum mortality charge, you
do not have to pay it separately from your pocket. It will be managed in your fund value in its own way.
But it will be levied on sum at risk. Sum at risk means suppose you
purchase a policy with premium of Rs. 0000 and you have insurance of Rs. 5 lakh and after a few years your fund value
becomes Rs. 5 lakh, then mortality charges will be levied only on the remaining Rs. 2 lakh,
if the fund value increases to Rs. 1, then no mortality charges, which means when
your fund from your insurance cover is 1 lakh. The value will increase and from that day onwards you
will also not be charged mortality charges Partial withdrawal In this policy
, along with systematic withdrawal, you will also get the option of partial withdrawal You
can do partial withdrawal after 5 years How much can you do Up to 20% of the fund value You can
do parcel withdrawal in a year The maximum you can do is two annual premiums should
remain in the policy The maximum you can withdraw in this policy up to the remaining amount
Total policy is 10 years If you get a top up done in this policy, then you
will be able to get parcel withdrawal of the top up also after 5 years You
will be able to withdraw parcel from the top up amount only after 5 years So, whenever you withdraw parcel for the first time,
if you do a top up, then first your parcel will be withdrawn from the top up Later
on, it will be from your regular plan The minimum amount in this you will get a parcel of Rs.000
You will have to do it as a withdrawal. In this policy, you will get the option of switching. If
you have invested in a fixed portfolio
or have invested in a fixed strategy, then you will be able to do unlimited switching there.
But if you have invested in a particular fund, for example, you
have invested in a maximizer fund or
have invested in different funds in this way, then you
can switch from one fund to another four times in a year. Most of the customers do not do it even once, but
switching should be done. Whenever the market goes down, you should switch your fund to equity. If
you want to take high risk, then definitely switch there. But if the market goes down sometimes,
like it did during the time of Covid, then if you have a debt fund as well as an income
fund, then you should invest there so that your money does not go down. This switching
is free of cost and you can do it from home through an online portal or
through your agent. As I told you, you can do systematic withdrawal
where you can withdraw up to 12%. I have taken the 12 per cent. Now you must be thinking that here
in Ajman, I have told you 12 per cent, what actual returns are you getting. Here you
get a lot of funds to invest in. If you
want to invest in equity funds, you will get a lot of equity funds. If you
want to invest in balanced funds, you can do that. That is, on the safe side, if you
want to invest in debt funds, you can do that. Let us assume that you can see here
the returns for one year, two years, three years, four years, five years and since the inception of this fund, the returns
will be shown here that from 2009 to 2011, 2015, since the time this fund was launched, what returns
are you getting from it. For example, if we look at the returns of one year, then the value enhancer fund has a one-year
return of more than 50 per cent. It has tax-free returns of 50 per
cent. Its returns since inception are also
around 15 per cent. This fund was launched in July 2018. Look at other funds where the return is 16%.
India Growth Fund has been launched since 2019. India
is growing very well right now. You must have seen that the stock market is also growing very well. So
this is how investment is made in Indian companies. Here you can see that its
inception date is June 2017.
An investment of 6573 million rupees has been made in it. Its benchmark is Nifty 100.
The current NAV is running at ₹. Its fund manager is Jitendra Arora ji and he
is managing 25 funds. Age of Now, out of which 22 are equity funds and three are balance funds.
Look at this, you will see the graph from 2020 itself that from where it started and how
it has come to which NAV, okay, you can see here. Plus
if you look at the investment here, an investment of 98% is being made in equity related securities.
An investment of about 63 million rupees has been made in it.
There is also an investment of 2% in the money market. If there is no investment in fund,
then at 98 your money is going into equity, that too
according to Indian Growth Fund. Here
,
let me tell you about another fund, for example, the mid cap return
is also of 40 per cent. Nifty Mid Cap 150 is its benchmark. Currently, it
is getting NV of ₹. Balvinder Singh is its fund manager who will manage the fund for you. And
you can also see its returns. It started in 2023 at a NAV of around ₹. It
started in November 2023. In November 20224, see, the NAV has increased to
1387. It has also given returns of around 40 per cent.
If you want to see the NV history, you can see the NV history here as well.
And portfolio details, I will tell you again, here also your money
is going into equity at 99 per cent. Investment is being made in the money market at 1. And
if you see the portfolio details here
, in which financial sectors there are around 16 There is an investment of 8 per cent in manufacturing
sector, 8.37 per cent in infrastructure sector, so your investment is also being made in different
sectors, plus in which companies
are you investing, you have 2.34 in Sujan Energy, 2.23 in Max Healthcare,
1.79 in BSC Limited, from Indian Hotels, there is FB Fintech, there is Lupin, there is Federal
Bank, you can see IDFC First Bank, there is S Bank, there is Volta, Hindustan
Petroleum, here you are investing in so many companies,
the fund manager is investing for you in different companies in different sectors
and giving you good returns, so you can see these complete details.
You can see in which funds your money is going and how much percentage is going.
Now if you look at the returns of balance fund,
you are getting returns of up to 36% in balance fund as well. If you look at the returns from Inception, the return since 2021 is 12%.
The investment of balance fund multi-cap fund is also there.
This fund has also given a return of 24% in the last one year. Even look at a debt fund, the debt fund which
was started on 2 November 2009, which is a safe type of FD, it also
has a return of 9.28% in the last one year since 2009. So you are absolutely safe,
if you invest in income fund, then where does your investment go
, the benchmark is Crisal Composite Bond Fund, but look at your investment here,
your entire investment is going towards debt fund, going into debt instrument
at 95% and money market is also safe, there is investment in money market at 5%.
If the market is going up, then invest in equity funds. If
the market is going down, then you can be safe. You can do free of cost switching.
You don't have to pay even a single rupee. You can switch instantly. You can do it online while sitting on your own.
You get a good tax free return by investing in different places.
You can do systematic withdrawals, partial withdrawals
. If you want to close the policy after 5 years, you can do it. If you want
to switch from one fund to another, you can do redirection. There is also
tax benefit. There is a tax benefit of up to Rs. 1.5 lakh in TC and the return on investing
up to Rs. 1 lakh in 101D is tax free. As for other benefits and features of the policy
, in this policy you will get the option of settlement
that when the policy matures, suppose you
do not want to take your XY fund value immediately, but you want to take it in the next 5 years in yearly, quarterly, monthly mode
through ECS. So you can take this policy, let's talk about premium redirection,
let's assume that you
have selected any one of the four strategies at the time of inception of the policy, now whatever premium you want to pay in future,
suppose you have paid premium for two-three years, now suppose your fourth premium is coming
and you feel that no, I do not want to invest in this strategy and
invest in a particular fund, suppose I
want to invest in a maximizer fund, then under redirection, this is not called switching, it is called redirection,
this fourth premium of yours, suppose it is Rs. 1 lakh, then you can invest
the entire premium in maximizer fund, so in this way you
will also get the benefit of redirection, plus in this policy you will also get the benefit of top up,
you can do a minimum top up of Rs. 000, in front of top up you will also
get 1.25 times insurance cover and you will also get sum, then in this policy, if you want to surrender after 5 years,
then you can surrender, before that if you If you close it, your policy will go to the discontinuance
fund and after that, if you want to withdraw money only after 5 years, you
will be able to withdraw it. Talking about the loan, since it is a ULIP policy, it
is a unit insurance policy and a market-based policy, loan is not available. Talking about the income tax benefit,
if you pay premium up to ₹ 5 lakh in section 10 of income tax, you
get rebate in it. You can invest up to ₹ 5 lakh in this policy, then the returns on it
will be tax free under section 1010D of income tax. Talking about the free look period and
grace period, it will be for 30 days. After the policy comes home,
there is a free look period of 30 days, which if you
are not satisfied with the policy for some reason and want to cancel it, you can do it.
You get a grace period of one month at the time of renewal premium. Talking about the revival period,
if for some reason you are not able to pay the premium on time, then you have 3 years of time
during which you can make a late investment in the policy. After paying fees etc. If
there is a need to get a medical test done, then after getting that done, you can revive the policy or start it again.
Finally, if I surprise you, then this is one of the best Uli plans across all 24
life insurance companies because waiver of premium rider is there in very few companies,
on death the premium gets waived, income starts, death benefit is available immediately, the company
pays the premium and you get it back on maturity, there is tax, there is SWP, there
is partial withdrawal, there are 23 such funds where you can get very good returns whose
past performance has been 20-25, there are debt funds, hybrid funds, you
can do free switching, on investment up to Rs. 10 lakh you get the benefit of ATC as well and tax at Rs. 10
Free income is also coming, it
is a brand like ICICI, so according to me this is a very good plan, if you want to purchase this plan,
if you want to purchase it from me then you can call me on 0940 3412, if you want to compare it with other company's Uli
plan then you can message me for
consultation and comparison and then purchase. And before leaving, I
have more than 3 videos on YouTube, which will help you in financial planning, will
help in insurance related planning, will help you in child education, marriage, retirement,
term policies, medi claim etc., you will easily get information on this channel, only
related videos are available on the channel, thank you so much.